Zhi WANG

Associate Research Fellow
Department of Control Science and Intelligence Engineering
Nanjing University

Phone: +86 13160032505 https://heyuanmingong.github.io

Email: zhiwang@nju.edu.cn

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests include reinforcement learning (RL) algorithms and their applications on robotics. Specifically, I work on how learning algorithms can scale RL agents to dynamic environments (or "open" environments), allowing them to autonomously adapt to the non-stationary task distributions in real-world domains. This includes a wide range of topics such as incremental learning, lifelong learning, transfer learning, and meta-learning.

EXPERIENCE

2022.11-Now	Associate Research Fellow, <i>Nanjing University</i> Department of Control Science and Intelligence Engineering
2019.11-2022.10	Assistant Research Fellow, <i>Nanjing University</i> Department of Control Science and Intelligence Engineering
2022	Visiting Scholar, Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences Visiting tutors: Professor Yuanheng Zhu, Dongbin Zhao
2019	Visiting Scholar, <i>University of New South Wales</i> Visiting tutor: Professor <i>Daoyi Dong</i>

EDUCATION

2015.09-2019.10	Ph.D. City University of Hong Kong
	Machine Learning, Department of Systems Engineering and Engineering Management
	Supervisor: Professor Han-Xiong Li
2011.09-2015.08	B.E. Nanjing University
	Automation, Department of Control and Systems Engineering

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

- Hongyu Ding, Yuanze Tang, Qing Wu, Bo Wang, Chunlin Chen, **Zhi Wang***, "Magnetic field-base reward shaping for goal-conditioned reinforcement learning," *IEEE-CAA Journal of Automatica Sinica*
- Junyi Wang, **Zhi Wang***, Huaxiong Li, and Chunlin Chen, "Adaptive noise-based evolutionary reinforcement learning with maximum entropy," *Acta Automatica Sinica*
- Donghan Xie, **Zhi Wang***, Chunlin Chen, Daoyi Dong, "Depthwise convolution for multi-agent communication with enhanced mean-field approximation," *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems*

- **Zhi Wang**, Chunlin Chen, and Daoyi Dong, "Lifelong incremental reinforcement learning with online Bayesian inference," *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems*
- **Zhi Wang**, Chunlin Chen, and Daoyi Dong, "Instance weighted incremental evolution strategies for reinforcement learning in dynamic environments," *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems*
- Yuanyang Zhu, **Zhi Wang***, Chunlin Chen, and Daoyi Dong, "Rule-based reinforcement learning for efficient robot navigation with space reduction," *IEEE-ASME Transactions on Mechatronics*
- **Zhi Wang** and Han-Xiong Li, "Dissimilarity analysis-based multimode modeling for complex distributed parameter systems," *IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics: Systems*
- **Zhi Wang**, Han-Xiong Li, and Chunlin Chen, "Incremental reinforcement learning in continuous spaces with policy relaxation and importance weighting," *IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems*
- **Zhi Wang**, Han-Xiong Li, and Chunlin Chen, "Reinforcement learning-based optimal sensor placement for spatiotemporal modeling," *IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics*
- **Zhi Wang**, Chunlin Chen, Han-Xiong Li, Daoyi Dong, and Tzyh-Jong Tarn, "Incremental reinforcement learning with prioritized sweeping for dynamic environments," *IEEE-ASME Transactions on Mechatronics*
- **Zhi Wang** and Han-Xiong Li, "Incremental spatiotemporal learning for online modeling of distributed parameter systems," *IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics: Systems*
- **Zhi Wang**, Wei Bi, Yan Wang, and Xiaojiang Liu, "Better fine-tuning via instance weighting for text classification," *AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence*

Note: *indicates the corresponding author

TEACHING

- <Deep Reinforcement Learning>, mainly for postgraduates, 2019–Now
- <Introduction to Automation>, for undergraduates, 2019–2022
- < Digital Circuits>, for undergraduates, 2022-Now

SOCIAL SERVICES

- Reviewer for leading journals and top conferences
 - IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems
 - IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics
 - IEEE/ASME Transactions on Mechatronics
 - IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics: Systems
 - IEEE-CAA Journal of Automatica Sinica
 - AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence
- Program Chair and Associate Editor for special sessions of international conferences
 - IEEE Conference on Systems, Man, and Cybernetics, 2023, 2022, 2021
 - IEEE International Conference on Networking, Sensing, and Control, 2020

INVITED TALKS

• Lifelong reinforcement learning for dynamic environments

- 2022.12, The 4th Distributed Artificial Intelligence (DAI) Conference Inviter: Professor Yan Zheng

- 2022.12, Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences Inviter: Professor Yuanheng Zhu

Yi

- 2022.12, Tongji University Inviter: Professor Peng

• Incremental reinforcement learning for dynamic environments

- 2020.12, University of Electronic Science and Technology of China Inviter: Professor Xiaoting Wang

- 2020.12, University of Science and Technology of China Inviter: Professor Lindong Liu

- 2019.04, University of New South Wales Inviter: Professor Daoyi Dong

• Instructor of summer course "Deep Reinforcement Learning"

- 2022.07, University of Science and Technology of China Inviter: Professor Lindong Liu

HONORS AND AWARDS

• Doctor of Innovation and Entrepreneurship in Jiangsu Province, 2020–2022

• Outstanding Academic Performance Award, City University of Hong Kong, 2018

• Research Tuition Scholarship, City University of Hong Kong, 2018